# AMANDA PARTLOW

DATA ANALYST

#### **DATA EXPERIENCE**

#### **DATA ANALYST**

Nashville Software School | 2020

An intensive, full-time program with hands-on training in the most widely-used tools, including Excel, Python, SQL, Tableau, and Power BI

- Worked with real data to solve problems, create compelling visualizations, and generate insight
- Focus on teamwork, team building, and leadership
- Analytical reasoning through hands-on training on every stage of the analytics workflow

#### **Project Highlights**

- <u>Capstone Nashville Public School Disparities:</u> Using data culminated from The TN Department of Education, The Census Bureau, and several other sources, created dashboard to look at differences in school ratings among schools with children of varying demographic backgrounds. Used a mixture of Python, SQL, and Tableau to create a dashboard that illustrates how factors such as race and socio-economic status influence the quality of school a child will attend.
- <u>Airplane Etiquette</u>: Used data from a FiveThirtyEight survey regarding various social aspects of airplane travel. Used Excel for data cleaning and simple aggregation and Tableau to create a traveler's guide to polite airplane travel. The final dashboard illustrates geographically who thought different airplane activities were rude, such as putting your seat back and asking to switch seats with other passengers.
- <u>Baseball Statistics</u>: Used SQL and several relational databases compiled by Sean Lahman to explore data and draw conclusions about baseball throughout the years, such as which colleges produce the highest paying pros. This was a group project that utilized an understanding of primary keys, foreign keys, and different types of join to gather the right sources of data together.
- PoKi: Drawing from a CSV of over 60,000 children's poems provided by Cornell University, created a Power BI dashboard to illustrate the differences in kids thought processes and interests as they age from 1st through 12th grade. Used Excel to clean data and create new insights such as using a complex function that searched each poem for certain keywords in order to categorize the topics of the poems. The end result was a dashboard that allows the user to search poetry based on topics, filter theme-frequency and emotion by gender and grade, and observe how feelings and interests evolve over childhood.

#### OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **OUTCOMES DATA ANALYST AND PROGRAM COORDINATOR**

Girls Inc. of Chattanooga | 2014 - 2020

- Oversaw a team of interns who compiled and entered data
- Streamlined outcomes data process for reporting, helping to secure over \$500,000 in funding and dozens of new and ongoing community partnerships
- Analyzed outcomes data and compared to national and local data in order to develop reports, drive grant fulfillment, and support community partners
- Wrote and implemented an afterschool program focused on science, technology, engineering, and math for fourth and fifth grade girls

#### **CENTER CONSULTANT**

FedEx Office | 2012 - 2018

- Used programs such as Photoshop, Excel, and Word to edit and create customer documents while collaborating with customers
- Juggled up to half a dozen complicated production orders at a time while assisting customers with retail needs in a fast-paced, highly dynamic work environment

#### **CAREGIVER**

Howard Center | 2010 - 2011

- Cared for and provided day-to-day support to residents with schizophrenia
- Trained extensively in the areas of mental health and first aid

#### CONTACT

912 399 7521 amandajpartlow@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/amandapartlow/ github.com/amandapartlow

#### **ABOUT ME**

When I was young, I used to calculate and chart every aspect of my life from daily productivity time graphs to budgeting tools to hypothetical grade calculations based on various test outcomes. So when I began working with data in a professional capacity five years ago, it clicked that this was something I needed to turn into a full time career. I love the feel of numbers, and being able to use them to create visualizations and inform decisions. I am energetic, hardworking and extremely motivated, I have been described by coworks as a "little go-getter." I love to solve puzzles of all kinds, and I am on a constant quest to soak up knowledge and new skills. My background in education in the non-profit world has given me strong roots in empathizing and effectively communicating with a wide range of people.

#### **TECHNICAL TOOLS**

Microsoft Excel
SQL
Python
Power BI
Tableau
Adobe Photoshop
Microsoft Word, Outlook, PowerPoint

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Data Cleaning
Data Profiling
Data Analyzation
Data Visualization
Interactive Reporting

### **EDUCATION**

#### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

15-Week, Full-Time Data Analytics Bootcamp | March 2020 - June 2020

# UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE AT CHATTANOOGA

Bachelor of Science in Middle Grades Education: Math and Science | Jan 2012 - May 2014